<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Going With God</title>
    <link>https://www.goingwithgod.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Going With God</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 05:09:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.goingwithgod.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Work in Progress?</title>
      <link>https://www.goingwithgod.com/work-in-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.goingwithgod.com/work-in-progress/</guid>
      <description>Nothing I publish is perfect.
Everything I publish is a &amp;ldquo;work in progress&amp;rdquo; to some degree or another.
I once wrote about Agile Blogging. My thought was, &amp;ldquo;What if I could incrementally build up content, rather than have to sit down and write until all my thoughts were fully fleshed out and &amp;lsquo;perfect&amp;rsquo;? What would that look like?&amp;rdquo;
I took some cues from the Agile software development methodology, and decided that I&amp;rsquo;d value continual enhancement and gradual build-up of my content, over and above long time commitments and perfection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My, How You’ve Changed</title>
      <link>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/family/2015-11-30-my-how-youve-changed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 05:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/family/2015-11-30-my-how-youve-changed/</guid>
      <description>1 Corinthians 15:51–54 (ESV)
Behold! I tell you a mystery. We shall not all sleep, but we shall all be changed, in a moment, in the twinkling of an eye, at the last trumpet. For the trumpet will sound, and the dead will be raised imperishable, and we shall be changed. For this perishable body must put on the imperishable, and this mortal body must put on immortality. When the perishable puts on the imperishable, and the mortal puts on immortality, then shall come to pass the saying that is written: “Death is swallowed up in victory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodnight, Grandpa</title>
      <link>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/family/2015-04-02-goodnight-grandpa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 19:32:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/family/2015-04-02-goodnight-grandpa/</guid>
      <description>“But we do not want you to be uninformed, brothers, about those who are asleep, that you may not grieve as others do who have no hope. For since we believe that Jesus died and rose again, even so, through Jesus, God will bring with him those who have fallen asleep.” 1 Thessalonians 4:13–14 (ESV)
He’s fallen asleep. That’s all. No need to grieve like one with no hope. Grieve, but grieve in hope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on Love: Asking Too Much, or Giving Too Little?</title>
      <link>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/bible/2015-02-19-reflections-love-asking-much-giving-little/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 04:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/bible/2015-02-19-reflections-love-asking-much-giving-little/</guid>
      <description>1 John 3:16-17 (ESV) 16 By this we know love, that he laid down his life for us, and we ought to lay down our lives for the brothers. 17 But if anyone has the world’s goods and sees his brother in need, yet closes his heart against him, how does God’s love abide in him?
Knowing Love In the first part of verse 16, we are given the essence of what love really is:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiencing a Miracle – A Review of &#34;Caged In&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/reflections/2014-12-11-experiencing-miracle-review-caged/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 04:20:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/reflections/2014-12-11-experiencing-miracle-review-caged/</guid>
      <description>Home sweet home I had just returned from an amazing journey in the mountains at the base of the Himalayas. Some fellow classmates and I had organized a team to visit a small village school that had no clean drinking water. We built them the first of three water cisterns, and by golly, it was holding the water that was being piped to it from a fresh mountain spring. Success!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple words. Powerful cross.</title>
      <link>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/bible/2014-05-20-simple-words-powerful-cross/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 18:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/bible/2014-05-20-simple-words-powerful-cross/</guid>
      <description>1 Corinthians 1:17 (ESV) — 17 For Christ did not send me to baptize but to preach the gospel, and not with words of eloquent wisdom, lest the cross of Christ be emptied of its power.
Whenever the topic of faith in Jesus enters a conversation, my attention is immediately heightened to what I’m saying. Do I sound “intelligent”? Is my “credibility” as a “rational person” at stake when I start talking about the gospel?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is God&#39;s &#34;God-ness&#34; Enough?
</title>
      <link>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/bible/2014-01-06-is-gods-god-ness-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 13:32:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/bible/2014-01-06-is-gods-god-ness-enough/</guid>
      <description>Isaiah 41:10 (ESV)
Fear not, for I am with you; be not dismayed, for I am your God; I will strengthen you, I will help you, I will uphold you with my righteous right hand.
“I am with you”, says God. “Therefore, fear not.”
“I am your God”, says God. “Therefore, be not dismayed.”
In righteousness God promises strength, help, and upholding. “I will”, God says. “I will.”
Faith sees these words and embraces them as reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Father&#39;s Day 2.0</title>
      <link>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/family/2013-06-16-fathers-day-2-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 16:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/family/2013-06-16-fathers-day-2-0/</guid>
      <description>How is it that the father of a 5.5 month old baby boy (me!) is claiming to celebrate “Father’s Day 2.0”??
My wife wrote a very compelling blog post last year around Father’s Day. You can find it over at her blog, “Eve’s Daughter”.
I love the argument she presents – how we wholeheartedly believe that life begins at conception and that our baby boy is 5.5 months old since birth, but he has existed as a human being for well over a year now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Old is Silas Allen?</title>
      <link>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/family/2013-03-31-how-old-is-silas-allen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 14:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/family/2013-03-31-how-old-is-silas-allen/</guid>
      <description>“Ooooohh, now… how old is he??” I love this question. Really! I do! Every time I’m asked I get to talk about my kid, and that’s always fun. But today, things just got even more fun. Now, instead of just telling people his approximate age, I can show them his precise age down to the second!
As some of you know, I’ve been nerding out on learning to build iOS apps for iPhone and iPad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of &#34;Love to the Uttermost&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/bible/2013-03-24-review-of-love-to-the-uttermost-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 21:09:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/bible/2013-03-24-review-of-love-to-the-uttermost-2/</guid>
      <description>As a dad looking for a way to lead my family in devotions for Holy Week, I was thrilled when I heard that Desiring God had released a daily devotion guide for this week leading up to Easter. Courtney and I (and Silas, though he was still preparing for his big day) really enjoyed reading the Advent series during Christmas, so I was excited to see the Holy Week counterpart, “Love to the Uttermost”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delight yourself in the Lord, and he will give you… What?</title>
      <link>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/bible/2013-03-23-delight-yourself-in-the-lord-and-he-will-give-you-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 16:27:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/bible/2013-03-23-delight-yourself-in-the-lord-and-he-will-give-you-what/</guid>
      <description>“Delight yourself in the Lord, and he will give you the desires of your heart“, the Psalmist writes in chapter 37 verse 4.
Question: What is the promise of this verse? What exactly does “give you the desires of your heart” mean?
Confession: I am so caught up in myself and in the world I see. Sadly, my vision of true worth and true beauty is far from 20-20. My senses just don’t pick up on what really satisfies – I’ve become desensitized… dull… I feel like I’ve entirely missed the point of Psalm 37:4 for the majority of my life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet The Bancrofts</title>
      <link>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/family/2013-03-16-meet-the-bancrofts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 00:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/family/2013-03-16-meet-the-bancrofts/</guid>
      <description>I recently starred in a documentary. Well… Sort of…
By “starred”, I mean it was basically all about my son, Silas, and Courtney and I were in it as “support roles”. But who needs the details, right? It’s probably better that my face appears less anyway – Silas’ face is way cuter.
Seriously though, I was blown away by the talent of Ms. Jordan Moss. She did this video as a project for her degree – I give it an A+ (but of course I may be a tiny bit biased).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who’s Who?  Commentary on Psalm 37:23</title>
      <link>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/bible/2013-03-12-whos-who/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 19:46:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/bible/2013-03-12-whos-who/</guid>
      <description>Psalm 37:23-24 was this past week’s Fighter Verse. As I worked through memorizing these verses, I lingered on verse 23 for some time.
“The steps of a man are established by the LORD, when he delights in his way.”
I say “I lingered” – actually, I got stuck on the grammar. I kept asking, “Who is he?” and “Who is h_is_?” in this verse . A natural reading of the text suggests a solution, but in typical Andrew style, I over-analyzed it and my mind spun for a while trying to figure out if I was really right about the conclusion or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remaining with God = Going with God</title>
      <link>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/reflections/2011-11-13-remaining-with-god-going-with-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2011 15:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/reflections/2011-11-13-remaining-with-god-going-with-god/</guid>
      <description>1 Corinthians 7:17 , 24(ESV)
17 Only let each person lead the life that the Lord has assigned to him, and to which God has called him. This is my rule in all the churches. … 24 So, brothers, in whatever condition each was called, there let him remain with God.
It’s my observation that many Christians, perhaps even the majority, perceive an unnecessary difference between two categories of vocation: “secular” and “sacred”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think About These Things…</title>
      <link>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/bible/2011-07-16-think-about-these-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2011 10:52:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/bible/2011-07-16-think-about-these-things/</guid>
      <description>…What things?
According to Philippians 4:8 (ESV), the things to think about are those that are
true honorable just pure lovely commendable things that are of any excellence things that are worthy of praise I have several questions that come to mind from the list above, but I have a main one that has gripped me for the past few weeks.
It makes sense to think about things that have the qualities in Paul’s list above.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blessed to be a Blessing</title>
      <link>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/reflections/2011-05-28-blessed-to-be-a-blessing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2011 21:21:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/reflections/2011-05-28-blessed-to-be-a-blessing/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;God is not glorified when we keep for ourselves (no matter how thankfully) what we ought to be using to alleviate the misery of unevangelized, uneducated, unmedicated, and unfed millions&amp;#8221;. Desiring God p198 Oh the folly of a doctrine that would enable me to justify spending God-given resources on all kinds of luxurious purchases, believing that I can glorify God by simply being thankful that God gave me so much to buy them with!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Delivered Him Up?</title>
      <link>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/bible/2011-03-21-who-delivered-him-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 06:33:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.goingwithgod.com/blog/bible/2011-03-21-who-delivered-him-up/</guid>
      <description>…”who was delivered up for our trespasses and raised for our justification.” – Romans 4:25
Something amazing was drawn out of this verse for me as I listened to John Piper (www.desiringgod.org) preach through Romans 4:25 this week. The observation was essentially this: Jesus was delivered up to be crucified. The verb “delivered” is passive, meaning the action was performed by someone else. So the question then became, “Who delivered him up?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
